[MUSIC]
Hi, I'm Nat.
I was one of the original designers of the Xbox.
I've been working with
with computers since I was maybe seven years old and now I work on virtual reality.
(upbeat music)
- Computers are everywhere.
They're in people's pockets.
people's cars, will have them on their wrists, they might be in your backpack right now.
But, what makes a computer a computer?
What does make a computer a computer?
computer anyway.
And how does it even work?
As humans, we've always built tools to help us solve problems.
tools like a wheelbarrow, a hammer, or a printing press, or a tractor trailer.
All of these inventions helped us with manual work.
Over time, people are
People began to wonder if a machine could be designed and built to help us with the
thinking work we do, like solving equations or tracking the stars in the sky.
Rather than moving or manipulating physical things like dirt and stone, these machines
would need to be designed to manipulate information.
The earliest computers were made out of wood and metal with mechanical levers and gears.
By the 20th century, though, computers started using electrical.
components. These early computers were really large and really slow. A computer
the size of a room might take hours just to do a basic math problem.
These machines are things of gleaming, very colored metal and numerous flashing lights.
already really awesome at the time and they were only manipulating numbers back then.
But now we can use them to talk to each other, we can use them to play games, control robots.
robots and do any crazy thing that you could probably imagine.
The computers we use today look really different from the earliest thinking machines.
And who knows what the computer
of tomorrow will be like. My hope is that you get to help decide what you want the computers
of tomorrow to look like.
(chimes)